내가 여러분의 영혼을 버리고
어디로 가겠습니까?
Where can I go from Your Spirit?
Where can I flee
from Your presence?
내가 여러분을 벗어나
어디로 가겠습니까?
내가 안식을 구할때,
If I go up to the heavens,
You're there.
여러분이 거기에 있을겁니다
If I rise on the wings of the dawn,
내가 비상의 날개를 펼치고,
저 바다 한편에 자리 할때,
if I settle on the far side of the sea,
even there,
바로 그곳에서,
Your Hand will guide me.
여러분이 나를 인도 할겁니다
There is no place you can go,
여러분은 아무데도 갈 수 없고,
no place you can be,
머무를곳도 없습니다,
where you are not in the presence
주 하나님의 품이 아니면
그 어디에도 존재 할 수 없습니다
of the Lord our God.
There is no thought
you can have,
주 하나님이 보시지 않는곳에선,
꿈 꾸지도 말고,
no dream
you can dream,
where the Lord our God
does not see.
아무것도 가지려 하지 마십시오
내가 안식을 구할때,
If I go up to the heavens,
You are there.
여러분이 그곳에 있을지니,
내가 비상의 날개를 펼치고,
If I rise on the wings of the dawn,
if I settle
on the far side of the sea,
저 바다 한편에 자리 할때,
even there,
그곳에서,
Your hand will guide me.
여러분이 나를 인도 할겁니다
If I make my bed in the depths,
내가 인식을 위해 거기에 누울때
You are there.
여러분이 거기에 있을겁니다
도로시? 우리 왔단다
Dorothy? We're back.
Dorothy?
도로시?
Naughty baby won't drink its milk!
개구장이 녀석!
우유를 안먹겠단 말이지?!
Jesus!
하나님, 맙소사!
도로시 (2008년 作)
자막제작 by 여왕의 귀환
Shh. Shh.
자, 자...
- No, please!
- Calm down.
- 안돼요, 제발!
- 진정해
You see what I mean?
토마스 모튼 박사 - 정신의학과장 -
상태가 어떻습니까?
정상은 아니군요
Absolutely normal.
담배 한대 주시겠어요?
Can I have a cigarette?
벌어지는 일들이...
Things are still very...
무척 혼란 스럽군요
confused.
There's no rush.
복잡하게 생각하지 마
You take all the time you want.
당신이 편한 시간을 잡으면 돼
Where should I begin?
어디서 부터 시작을 해야 하나요?
You wanted this case.
당신이 이런 사례를 원한거야
You knew how difficult it would be.
얼마나 어려운지는
잘 알고 있을테지
But you still wanted it.
하지만 아직도 하겠다면
You insisted.
누가 말리겠어
가겠어요
I wanted to go.
내가 원하는건...
I needed to.
이 숨막히는 도시를 떠나는 거예요
I had to get away
before the city smothered me.
- 혼수상태에 빠진 아기 -
- 싸이코 보모 도로시 사건의 의문 -
바짝 쫒아 왔잖아!
They're riding our backside!
Hurry up!
빨리 가!
어서!
더 빨리!
Faster!
Go! Step on it! Step on it!
밟아! 더 밟아! 밟으라구!
도와 주게나
Come on, lads.
The Lord giveth,
하나님이 보내시고
and the Lord taketh away.
하나님이 거두어 가시는 거지
Look over there!
저쪽에 보세요!
You all right, miss? You're okay?
괜찮으세요, 부인?
다친데 없어요?
I wasn't speeding.
전 속도도 내지 않았어요
차 두대가 다운힐 경주를
하고 있었어요
There were two cars racing each other.
경주를 했다고요?
Racing each other?
An orange and a blue one.
오렌지색 차량과
파란색 이었어요
다이버용 시계라
튼튼한 놈이군요
It's hardly a diving watch you've got there.
Let it dry.
말려봐요
하루 이틀정도 지나면
다시 작동 할겁니다
It'll tick again in a day or two.
Well, we can't
sit around here all night.
가시죠, 밤새 이러고
있을순 없잖아요
Wait. There's a back entrance.
잠깐만요, 그쪽은 뒷문이예요
정신과 의사시래요
The psychiatrist.
- 글로리아
- 자네, 사고나는 소리 들었나? 응?
- Gloria.
- Did you have a bit of an accident, huh?
어서와요, 보안관
All right, Colin?
You come with me.
절 따라 오세요
우선 옷부터 말려야 겠군요
We'll get you dried off.
여기예요, 비좁긴 하지만
지내시기는 편할거예요
Here it is. Isn't a suite,
but I hope you'll be comfortable.
다른 담요를 몇장 더 갖다 드릴께요
I'll maybe get you another blanket.
요 몇일은 밤에 추웠어요
It's been cold these last few nights.
The heating's been on all day,
난방을 하루 종일 하니까
뜨거운물은 잘 나올거예요
so there should be
plenty of hot water.
여기가 욕실이구요
This is the bathroom.
목욕물 받아 드릴까요?
Should I run a bath for you?
다른 타올로 갖다 드릴게요
I'll bring you up another towel.
Don't take any notice of the menfolk.
여기 남정네들 이야기는
신경 쓰지 마세요
겉으로만 그렇지, 속으로는
친절한 사람들이예요
They're decent enough men at heart.
Be back up in a few minutes.
다시 올게요
저녁거리 좀 갖다 드릴게요
Bring you up a bit of supper.
There you are.
여기 계셨군요
잘 주무셨어요?
Did you sleep well?
전자기타 소리 때문에
밤새 잠을 설쳤어요
Not with an electric guitar
playing over my head all night.
그럴리가요
That's funny.
There's no one here but ourselves.
여긴 우리밖에 안사는데..
꿈을 꾸신 모양이네요
You were maybe dreaming.
It's a lovely day.
날이 참 좋군요
하얀 푸딩을
좀 갖다 드릴게요
I'll get you some white pudding.
It's delicious. You'll love it.
무척 맛있어서,
좋아 하실거예요
How long will it take to fix this?
수리하는데 얼마나 걸릴까요?
It's scrap.
완전히 박살 났어요
부품 교체하고,
이것 저것 손보면..
Even if we could get the parts,
비용이 차값만큼
나오겠군요
it would cost more
than the car's worth.
렌트카는 없나요?
Can I rent a car?
I've only got that pickup over there.
저 쪽에 하나 있긴 하오만..
- 안전 하겠지요?
- 당신 BMW 만큼 말인가요?
- Is it safe?
- How safe was your BMW?
I'll get you the keys.
열쇠를 갖다 드리겠소
이해를 못하시나 본데,
제가 여기에 온 이유는..
You must understand that I'm here
as much as for your sake
as for Dorothy's.
도로시와 당신의
이익을 위해서예요
You're already making excuses for her?
벌써 그녀를 용서 하라는거요?
I'm trying to find out the truth.
진실을 알고 싶어요
The truth?
진실이라구요?
The truth is...
진실은 말이죠...
you'll find some name for her condition,
수년동안 그녀의 상태를 보면,
and in another couple of years,
다 알수 있소
she'll be out there abusing
someone else's child,
그녀는 저기서 다른 사람의
아기에게 폭행을 가했소
maybe even her own.
자기 아이한테도 그럴거요
Can you tell me
what happened that night?
그날밤 있었던 일을
이야기 해주시겠어요?
That was the first time
we used Dorothy as a babysitter.
도로시를 보모로
부른건 처음이었어요
I had my doubts,
but the pastor said she was all right.
걱정을 많이 했는데
목사님이 괜찮을거라 하더군요
Dorothy? We're back.
도로시? 우리 왔단다
Dorothy?
도로시?
개구장이 녀석!
우유를 안먹겠단 말이지?!
Naughty baby won't drink its milk!
Jesus!
하나님, 맙소사!
내 아기야
He's my baby.
He's my baby. He's my baby!
내 아기라니까!
내 아기라구!
- 아기를 이리 줘!
- 내 아기라니까!
- Get away from him!
- He's my baby!
Hello, shit face!
안녕? 쭈그렁탱이
What have you done?
무슨 짓을 한 거야?
What have you done!
무슨짓을 한 거냐구?
무슨짓을 했나 묻고 있잖아!
나와, 어서 나와!
Come on. Come on!
목사님 저희는 육지로 가야해요
Pastor, you gotta
let us on to the mainland.
It's an emergency. Please!
긴급상황이라구요, 제발요!
이번 일은 예외로 하기로 하지
In this case, we'll make an exception.
그럼, 제가 지원요청을 할게요
아마 헬기를 보내 줄겁니다
Well, I'll call for assistance.
They'll send a helicopter.
그년은 미친년이예요
She's a fuckin' nutcase.
Ask Paul Fallon's son Jake
what he thinks of her.
재이크한테 물어 보세요
그녀를 어떻게 생각하나..
Hello, Dorothy.
안녕, 도로시
I'm Dr. Morton,
난 모튼 박사야
but you can call me Jane.
그냥 제인이라고 불러
You were expecting me, weren't you?
날 기다리고 있었지?
You're very gifted.
미술에 소질이 있구나
Dorothy, we need to talk.
도로시, 우리 이야기 좀 할까?
Can I sit here?
앉아도 되겠니?
You know why I'm here, don't you?
내가 여기온 이유는 알고 있지?
네 애길 들어 주러 온거야
Look, all I want is to listen to you.
I'm not here to judge you,
and I won't make any decisions.
널 벌주러 온 것도 아니고
뭘 어쩌려는것도 아니야
Do you like babies?
아기들을 좋아 하니?
무슨 아기요?
What baby?
There was no baby.
I wasn't even there.
거기엔 아기가 없었어요
난 거기에 없었다구요
I don't want to speak anymore.
더 이상 이야기
하고 싶지 않아요
아무도 내 이야기를
들어 주지 않아요
Nobody listens to me.
Nobody.
아무도요
내가 듣고 있잖니
I'm listening.
And I'll understand you.
난 널 이해할수 있단다
도로시
Dorothy.
날 믿어 봐
Trust me.
So where were you if you
weren't at the Kearsleys'?
커스키씨네에 없었다면
어디에 있었던 거야?
I said my prayers,
하늘에 맹세컨데
전 자고 있었어요
and I went to bed.
아침까지 말예요
And I woke up in the morning
in my bed.
계속 침대에 있었어요
Do you remember anything else?
뭔가 기억 나는건 없니?
대답하기 싫어요
I'm sick of all your questions.
Okay.
그래
좋아, 그럼 우리
입장을 바꾸어 볼까?
Well, why don't we just
swap places, then?
You ask me questions.
네가 내게 질문을 하렴
I can ask you questions?
저 더러 질문을 하라구요?
그 아이가 한짓이라고
생각해요?
You think she's guilty, don't you?
I'm just doing the first psychological
assessment in this case.
저는 단지 정신분석적인
상담을 할뿐이예요
상담이라구요?
Case?
피해자는 아기라구요
This case is a child.
충분히 고통 받았다구요
And she has suffered enough.
It's up to the court
to decide what happens.
무슨일이 있었는지
아는게 우선이예요
I promise I'll do what's best for her.
그녀에게 최선의
방책을 강구 할겁니다
"Curiosity.
"호기심이란...
죄스러움인가
아님 문제점인가?"
Sin or flaw?"
That's enough now!
그만들 해!
100번씩 써보고
Write that out 100 times
내일 아침까지 제출 하도록
and show me in the morning.
수업 끝!
Now go!
So you're the doctor, too?
진료도 하시는군요?
네, 그렇소
I am.
도로시를 얼마나 돌보셨나요?
How long have you
been looking after Dorothy?
Not since she was 13.
13살 이전부터였소
Healthy child, isn't she?
지극히 정상적이었네요
Here on the island,
we live a clean, healthy life.
이섬에서는 모두들 무공해에
건강한 삶을 누리고 있습니다
우리의 신앙 또한 한 몫을 하지요
Our faith shelters us.
그녀의 정신적인 문제를
언제쯤 눈치 채셨죠?
I suppose you just failed to notice
her mental illness?
도로시는 특별한 아이였소
Dorothy is a special child.
There is a place for her
in our community.
우리 친교회는 그녀를 위한 곳이오
이전에도 아기들을 괴롭혔나요?
Even if she did molest that baby?
하나님이 심판 하시는거지,
제가 하는게 아니오
It is the Lord's place to judge, not mine.
저 역시 그녀를 처벌 하려는게 아녜요
I'm not here to judge her, either.
그녀를 도우러 왔죠
I'm here to help her.
And she can be helped.
그녀는 도움을 받아야 해요
We have little faith in your science.
우린 당신네들이 말하는
과학을 믿지 않아요
어떻게 과학이 그녀의 영혼을
정화 시킬수 있단 말이요?
How can your science
fathom her pure soul?
모두가 하나님의 천사요
One of God's angels.
그 천사가 감옥에 가게 생겼어요
An angel that might end up in prison.
They're not really fond
of women in here, are they?
여기는 외지 여자가
온적이 없나봐요?
It's a very devout community.
여긴 매우 종교적인 곳이 랍니다
신앙심이 매우 강해요
They take their faith very seriously.
당신은 신자가 아니신가봐요?
You're not a believer?
Me? No. Jeez.
저요? 전 아녜요
아주 어렸을때 부터요
Had enough of that when I was a kid.
You were born here?
여기 출신이세요?
Hmm. And raised.
흠.. 여기서 태어 났어요
Tried to escape the place,
but this island is like a magnet.
여기서 벗어 나려고
노력도 많이 했어요
그런데 이 섬은
이상한 자력이랄까...
당신도 벗어 날수 없을걸요
You can't escape.
There you are.
여기 있어요
이 섬에선 온통
하얀 음식들만 먹나 보죠?
What is it with white food and this island?
Hey, you've only three days of it.
당신이야 3일만 먹으면 되지만...
I have to live here.
여기서 사는 사람도 있답니다
I saw Dorothy today.
오늘 도로시를 만났어요
Yeah? How'd it go?
그래요? 어떻던가요?
내가 보기엔
죽음을 두려워 하더군요
I think she's scared to death.
- 무슨 죽음요?
- 그건 모르죠
- Scared of who?
- Don't know.
아마도 그녀 자신이겠죠
Herself, maybe.
강한 자기혐오는
충분한 동기가 되죠
Self-loathing can be a powerful driver.
Don't stare at her too long there, John.
존, 그녀를 너무
빤히 쳐다 보지마
살살 훔쳐 보는게
더 좋은거 알잖아
You know what these shrinks are like.
우리가 저랑 그짓하는
상상을 하는거 알기나 할까?
Wouldn't want her to know
we're thinking about fucking her.
Jesus.
미친놈
Dear Lord...
전지전능하신 하나님...
...once again we ask You
to shower Your blessings upon us.
...간절히 청하오니
저희에게 은총을
내려 주십옵소서
당신의 종
도로시를 보내오니...
Give unto Your servant Dorothy
the warmth of Your divine light.
하늘의 빛으로 온정을 베푸사
길을 인도 하시고
Let her find the way
through the halls of darkness.
어둠속에서 구원 하소서
Talk to me.
이야기 해 보렴
I know you're there, my son.
너 거기에 있지? 아들아
엄마한테 인사 해보렴, 아들아
Say hello to your mother, son.
생일 축하한다, 아들아
Happy Birthday, son.
아직 때가 아닌것 같군요
Perhaps this is not the time.
미안하네
I'm sorry, mate.
이봐!
Hello!
Janey!
제인!
What's up, lying shrink?
뭐하는거야? 디비져 자나?
우리가 깨운건가?, 우훗!
Hope we're not wakin' you up, eh!
우린 너가 필요 없어!
We don't need you!
Go back to where you belong!
너가 있던곳으로
얼른 돌아가!
Would you calm down, John?
존, 진정해
Come on, lad. They're only kids.
진정하래두, 애들 장난이 쟎아
- Christ Almighty!
- Jesus.
- 하늘이 보고 계신다!
- 오! 하나님
They're just kids, John.
존, 그냥 애들 장난이야
- It's just kids messing about.
- Let go of me.
- 젊은애들 객기일뿐이라구
- 그렇지 않아
개자식들!
다 죽여 버릴거야
I'll fucking kill them.
They were underneath
my window, waiting for me.
그들이 내방 창문 밑에서
날 기다렸다구요
Look, I can see you're upset.
화가 나는건 알겠소
But I know everybody on this island.
하지만 이곳 섬주민들은
내가 다 알아요
There aren't any teenagers
that fit that description.
여기 10대들중에는
그럴만한 놈이 없어요
Or orange cars, for that matter.
오렌색차나, 그런것들 말이오
You think I'm imagining this?
내가 헛것을 봤다고 생각해요?
No, but...
아니요, 하지만...
Look,
내말을 들어봐요
if it helps, I'll stick around
도움이 필요하면...
for the next couple of days, okay?
몇일 동안,
내가 당신을 돌봐 주겠소
You're leaving Sunday, right?
일요일이면 떠나실거요?
제 아들녀석이예요
That's my son.
Lives with his mother on the mainland.
제 엄마랑 육지에서 살고 있죠
아이 있어요?
Do you have any kids?
꼬마녀석 하나 있어요
A little boy.
Yeah?
그래요?
He died.
그런데 죽었어요
I'm sorry.
미안해요
괜찮아요
It's okay.
Um, I'd better go.
이만, 가봐야 겠어요
Thanks for the drink.
잘 마셨어요
When my sister died,
동생이 죽었을때,
there was no one else to look after her.
아무도 돌봐주는
사람이 없었어요
그래서 제가
도로시를 맡았죠
So it was natural she stay with me.
도로시 아버지는요?
What about Dorothy's father?
We never knew him.
아무도 몰라요
매이블은 문란한
아이가 아니었어요
Mabel wasn't promiscuous,
you understand?
She was fanciful,
상상력이 풍부하고,
flighty.
덜렁대긴 했지만...
She wasn't simple, either,
no matter what the others say.
평범 하진 않았지만,
사람들이 이야기 하는
그런 정도는 아니었어요
She just couldn't seem
to hold down a job
직장생활 할 마음이
없어 보였어요
until she took the job
in the funeral parlor,
그러다가 장의사에
취직을 했는데..
laying out the dead.
시체을 염하는 일이었어요
She liked that.
그일을 좋아 했어요
But she was a good mother.
하지만 좋은 엄마였어요
And she kept Dorothy safe
from the other children.
그앤 도로시를 다른 아이들과
어울리지 못하게 했어요
Do you have any idea why she was
bullied by the other children?
왜 그랬는지 아세요?
Because they hated
anyone or anything
그들은 무언가를
증오하면서 사니까요
that was different.
사고방식이 달랐어요
God help the child.
She was always different.
신은 아이들 편이라지만
그앤 그렇게 생각 안했어요
Did you ever think
she might be dangerous?
도로시가 위험했다고
생각 안하세요?
She never laid a hand on that baby.
아기한테 손도 대지
않았다더군요
She swore to me she didn't,
제게 맹세 했어요
and I believe her.
그말을 믿어요
왜 저를 도우려 하시는 거죠?
Why do you want to help me?
Because I've heard
you talk and...
네 이야기를 들었고...
I don't think you're here to help me.
여기에 절 도우러 오신게 아니죠?
I am here to help you.
널 도우러 온거야
도로시, 널 도울 수 있단다
I think I can help you, Dorothy.
이유를 말해줄까?
You know why?
내 재능이거든
Because it's my gift.
You're good at painting,
네가 그림을 잘 그리듯이
and I'm good at listening
and understanding.
난 잘 들어주고
잘 이해를 한단다
I can see why you like this place.
여길 좋아 하는 이유를
알것 같구나
It's beautiful.
너무 아름답구나
제가 꼬맹이일때,
My mother used to bring me here
when I was little.
엄마가 여기에
데려 오곤 했어요
We had this game
where we pretended to fly.
가짜로 나는척 하는
놀이를 같이 했었죠
항상 날고 싶었어요
I always wanted to fly.
만약 날수 있다면,
어딜 가고 싶은데?
Suppose you could fly.
Where would you go?
Nowhere.
정해진곳은 없어요
I'd just fly.
그냥 날으는 거죠
I'd never land.
착륙하지 않고
I'd fly as far as I could
날 수 있는 한 멀리요
until my last breath...
힘이 다하고,
숨이 다할때 까지...
and then fall.
그리곤 추락 하겠죠
And everything would be over.
모든게 끝나는 거죠
계집애 처럼 굴지마
Don't be shy, boy.
Hey.
Hey, Paul,
that son of yours won't take a drink.
폴, 자네 아들은
술을 안 마시려 하는데?
Go on, Jakey.
제이크, 한잔 마셔
The Pastor's not here.
목사도 없잖아
You're a man now, Jakey.
이제 진짜 남자 답구먼, 제이크
Uhh...
으...
The love of the Lord Jesus
하나님의 사랑은
is as the ocean, vast and endless.
바다 처럼 넓고, 영원 합니다
We see it lap upon our shore.
우린 눈으로
볼 수는 없지만
But know that it
laps on every shore.
온 누리에 펼쳐 있다는걸
알고 있습니다
The Lord sees all and knows all...
하나님은 모든것을
주관 하시고
the righteous and the sinner,
정의로운지, 비겁한지를...
the guilty and the blameless.
결백한지,
아닌지를 모두 알고 계십니다
Morning.
안녕하세요?
We had an appointment.
Do you remember?
약속을 했었는데,
잊으셨나 봐요?
I'm sorry.
죄송해요
I had to take Dorothy
경찰서에 다녀 왔어요
to the police station to sign the register.
진술서에 서명을
해야 한다기에...
She's ready for you now.
도로시는 여기 있어요
Hi, Dorothy.
안녕, 도로시
Do you want to come for a walk with me?
나랑 산책 가지 않으련?
I'll take you back to your aunt afterwards.
끝나고 이모한테
데려다 줄께
I want to stay with my auntie.
이모랑 여기 그냥 있을래요
Come on, child.
아가, 이러면 안돼
Come out.
다녀 오렴
Do as you're told, child.
시키는대로 하거라, 아가
That's a girl.
이젠 소녀쟎니
Your aunt is really nice
with you, isn't she?
이모가 네게
잘해 주시는구나?
Yes, she is.
네, 잘해주세요
She's looking after me
until Mommy comes back.
이모가 엄마가 돌아 오실때까지
보살펴 주시는 거예요
Where is your mommy?
엄마가 어디 계시는데?
She's out on the sea, sailing.
항해중이세요
She'll soon be back
to pick up her little Mimi
미미보고 싶어서,
곧 오신댔어요
and give her a pretty dress.
예쁜 옷도 사오신대요
M-Mimi?
미미라구?
How old are you?
너 몇살이지?
세살요
3.
Ain't she gorgeous?
나 대따 잘하죠?
So if you are Mimi,
네가 미미라면,
where has Dorothy gone?
도로시는 어디로 간거지?
She hasn't gone.
그녀는 어딜간게 아녜요
She's asleep.
자고 있어요
Asleep?
잔다구?
Yes.
네
In here. Right inside.
여기요, 제 안에 있어요
도로시가 네 안에
자고 있다구?
Dorothy is asleep inside of you?
You know what?
그거 아세요?
When her mother died,
그녀 엄마가 죽었을때,
I had to go to the funeral
장례식엔 내가 갔다 왔어요
because Dorothy was sleeping.
도로시는 자고 있었거든요
They don't let her out much.
그들은 도로시를 못 나오게 해요
Who doesn't let her out?
누가 그렇게 하지?
The others.
다른 사람들요
Who are they?
그들이 누군데?
I'm not allowed to tell.
말하면 안돼요
Why don't they let her out?
왜 그들이 그녀를
못나오게 하는거지?
Because she always
tries to kill herself.
항상 그녀는
자살하려고 하니깐요
Do you think my hair is pretty?
제 머리 예뻐요?
Do you like it?
이게 맘에 드니?
It's a gift. You can keep it on.
선물이야, 그걸로 하렴
Oh, thank you!
고마워요!
Tear that bitch's dress!
망할 드레스를 찢어 버려!
Dorothy!
도로시!
Trash it to ribbons!
리본 따윈 떼버려!
- Mimi!
- Shut your mouth, you little bitch!
- 미미!
- 입 닥쳐, 쪼끄만년아!
Aah! Bitch!
나쁜 년!
Who are you?
- 너 누구야?
Talk to me.
말해봐
Fuck off! Ugh!
엿 먹어! 썅!
Fuck off, slag!
지랄 하지마, 갈보야!
I'll kick your fuckin'...
거시길 걷어 차줄까?
Mommy.
엄마
엄마...
Mommy.
엄마
Mommy, where are you?
엄마, 어디있어?
Mommy, help me.
엄마, 도와줘
Help me.
도와줘...
Shh.
자...
Shh. It's over.
자... 다 끝났어
I'm here with you, baby.
나 여기있단다, 아가
How dare you!
무슨 짓이예요!
You should be ashamed of yourself.
부끄러운줄 아세요
Come on, pet.
이리오련, 우리 강아지
I would appreciate it
if you didn't interfere during the sessions.
치료중에는
방해 안 했으면 해요
Come on, darlin'.
어서, 아가
Go on now.
어서 가자
Good girl.
착하지
여보세요? 톰?
Hello? Tom?
제인이야
It's me, Jane.
그래, 대단해
Yeah. Great.
Well, it's a very interesting case.
그래, 아주 흥미로운 케이스야
I think I just might have to stay...
좀 더 머물러야 할 것 같...
Hello?
여보세요?
젠장
Shit.
뱃저!
Badger!
Oh. You scared me.
놀랐잖아요
죄송 합니다
Sorry.
섬에서 육지로는
통화가 잘 안돼요
It's difficult to call
the mainland from the island.
You going back to the village?
숙소로 돌아 가실건가요?
I am now, I suppose.
그래야겠어요
네 담배들은 전부 쓰레기야
Your fags are crap.
Haven't you got anything stronger?
좀 더 독한거 없어?
도로시?
- Dorothy?
- Uh-uh.
Wrong answer.
틀렸어
Want to try again?
한번 더 해볼까?
Well, I see Dorothy.
내가 보기엔
도로시 같은데
But you're listening to Mary.
메리님이 말씀 하는거야
Fuckin' weird, huh?
놀랍지, 응?
So where's Mimi?
미미는?
Little bitch couldn't keep her mouth shut.
쪼끄만년은
입이 싸서 말이야
And what about Dorothy?
그럼 도로시는?
Moaning or praying somewhere in here.
징징대면서
어딘가에 있겠지
She's only good for one thing...
그년은 써 먹을대가
딱 하나 뿐이야
taking the hangover after I get drunk.
메리님 한잔하고 나면
숙취 해소용으로 딱 이지
Is that what happened, Mary?
어떻게 돌아 가는거야, 메리?
You hurt the baby and let Dorothy face
the consequences?
네가 도로시 얼굴을 하고
아기를 해친거야?
I didn't lay a finger on that brat!
난 그 꼬마새끼 손댄적 없어!
But if she goes to jail for it,
there's no more drinking for you.
도로시가 감옥엘 가면
너도 술을 입에 못 댈텐데
You better take care, shrink!
몸 조심 하는게 좋을걸!
You're a stranger here.
넌 이방인이야
Stick your nose in too far,
그렇게 킁킁대고 다니다간
큰코 다칠거야
and you might lose it.
Trust me.
뻥 아니거든
You don't want that.
그렇게 되긴 싫지?
Who said you could feel me tits?
아, 별로 재미 없어!
Why are we going to
this shitty party anyway?
너 왜 자꾸 이따위
후줄근한 파티에 가자는거야?
춤 땡기고 싶으니까
Because I want to dance.
지랄하네
Fuck you.
And you know how well I can dance.
내가 춤을 얼마나
환상적으로 추는지 잘 알면서,
야!
Hey.
- Whoo-hoo!
맙소사!
Jesus.
나쁜놈들!
The bastards.
The bastards!
개 자식들!
반드시 댓가를 치르게 할거야
Christ. I'm gonna make them pay for this.
주의 이름을 걸고 할거야
By Christ I am.
얘들아, 이리오렴
Come on, lads. Come on.
Come on.
이리와
Mrs. Fallon.
팔론 부인
제인 모튼이라고 해요
Mrs. Fallon, I'm Jane Morton.
- 제가 여기온 이유는...
- 당신이 누군지 알아요
- I'm here to...
- I know who you are.
I need to speak to your son Jake.
아드님인 제이크하고
이야길 하고 싶은데요
You want to ask him
about that bitch Dorothy Mills?
도로시라는 나쁜년에 대해
물어 보려 그러슈?
그년은 거짓말쟁이요
걸레에다가 거짓말까지
She's a liar. A slut and a liar.
Why do you call her a slut?
왜 그렇게 부르죠?
뭐야?
What's the problem?
왜 어슬렁 거려?
What do you want?
Come to gloat?
기분이 꼬신가?
- 폴 진정하게
- 입 닥쳐
- Paul, calm down.
- Shut up!
You're getting a real kick
out of this, aren't you?
엉덩이를 걷어 채여야
여길 떠나겠어?
Messin' us around like guinea pigs.
우리가 무슨 실험 대상이야?
한마디 해줄까?
Well, let me tell you something.
This island is no
fucking laboratory, Doctor.
의사양반, 이 섬이 무슨
연구실이라도 되는줄 알아?
자, 폴, 그만하게
Come on, now, Paul. Drop it.
- All right, come on.
- You fucking bird.
- 됐어, 이리 와
- 재수 없는 년
어서 가요
Go on.
What the fuck is wrong with you people?
이 미치광이들은
다 뭐예요?
Just go.
그냥 가요
사유지
Get a grip on yourself, boy.
이보게 진정해
우린 잘못한거 없어
We didn't do anything wrong.
Not us.
그래 없지
죄책감 같은거 없어
We've nothing to be guilty about.
암, 없고 말고
No, sir.
Does nothing work on this bloody island?
이 삭막한 섬에선
아무도 일 안하나요?
- We'll see what we can do tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- 내일이나 되야해요
- 내일요?
오늘은 주일이랍니다
It's the Lord's day today.
교회로 가 봐
Go and see in the church.
그녀의 집에는 악마가 있어
She let the devil into her house.
하나님 아버지...
Our Father...
- Our King of glory...
- Our King of glories...
영광스런 아버지--
- 영광스런 아버지--
- We ask the Lord Jesus...
- 주님께 청하오니...
To bear your servant Dorothy...
당신의 종 도로시에게
생명을 주시고...
To bear your servant Dorothy...
당신의 종 도로시에게
생명을 주시고...
Once more into the realm of the dead.
또 다시 악마에 빠졌으니
- 전지전능하신 아버지께 기도 드리오니
Praise be to the Lord Jesus Christ,
- 아버지, 주 하나님...
- 제발요
- our Father, our King...
- I beg you.
제발 제게 이야기하게 해주세요
Please let him talk to me.
Please let him find the peace to talk.
이야기하고 평온을
찾을 수 있게 해주세요
Leave her alone!
그녀를 놔줘!
Through the blackness of eternity...
영원의 어둠을 뚫고...
Fuck all of you pigs!
야이 망할, 돼지새끼들아!
그만해!
Please stop!
It hurts!
아프단 말야!
Let her go
before I fucking kill you!
다 죽여 버리기전에
그녀를 놔 줘!
Please don't!
하지마!
Leave her alone!
그녀를 놔 줘요!
For God's sake.
맙소사!
Please don't. Please.
제발... 하지 마요
I shall notify the court in the morning
내일 아침
이 사실을 알리겠어요
that Dorothy must be taken
into custody immediately.
그리고 보호시설로
보내야 겠군요
She's not safe with you.
당신들은 위험해요
I'm taking her with me.
내가 데리고 가겠어요
Aah!
쌍년! 나쁜년!
You bitch! Bitch!
도로시, 진정 하거라
All right, Dorothy, calm down.
Oh, hey, it's the fucking sheriff!
잘 있었나,
좀만한 보안관 나리!
I asked you not to intervene.
끼어 들지 마요
Well, next time, I'll tie her up.
좋소, 하지만
다음번엔 묶어 버릴거요
My head.
아이고 머리야
좋아, 한가지 물어 보자
Well, you were kind of asking for it.
Dorothy?
도로시?
I'm not Dorothy.
도로시 아닌데?
I'm Kurt.
난 커트야
Well, nice to meet you, Kurt.
오 그래,
만나서 반가워, 커트
I'm Jane.
난 제인이야
Tell me what I can do to help you.
어떻게 도와주면 될까?
I always take the pain for her.
난 맨날 아파...
For Dorothy.
도로시 대신에...
I take the pain so she doesn't get hurt.
나만 아프고
도로시는 괜찮아
She wouldn't handle it.
그녀는 나 몰라라 해
That's very brave of you.
무척 용감 하구나
Yeah, well, I'm getting
a bit bored with it now.
난 이제 질렸어,
신물이 난다구
And I don't want to go to jail.
그리고 난 감옥에 가기 싫어
If Dorothy goes to jail,
we'll all go, won't we?
만약 도로시가 감옥 가면,
우리 모두 가게 되는거지?
Yes.
맞아
But you have to help me.
날 도와 줘
Were you there at the Kearsleys'?
너도 그자리에 있었지?
- Did you see the baby?
- No, no.
- 아기를 봤어?
- 아냐, 아냐
I can't talk. Duncan won't let me.
말 못해,
던칸이 하지 말래
- Who's Duncan?
- Duncan's the boss.
- 던칸은 누구야?
- 대장이야
Where is he? Can I talk to him?
그는 어디있는데?
얘기 할 수 있을까?
Trust me, you don't want
anything to do with him.
던칸하곤 아무것도
하려고 하면 안돼
You, especially. He'd kill you.
당신을 죽일꺼야
Tell Duncan that I want to speak to...
던칸에게 말해
내가 이야기 좀 하잔다고
돌아 와, 개 자식아!
Come back here, bastard!
개 자식! 망할!
Bastard! Shut it!
좀 잡아줘요
Hold her down for me.
도로시
Dorothy.
No.
안돼
내가 아기를 죽인거죠,
그렇죠?
I killed the baby, didn't I?
말 해줘요, 제발요
Tell me. Tell me, please.
- 도로시?
- 뭐 하는거야? 안돼
- Dorothy?
- What are you doing? No.
- 약속할께...
- 그만 둬
- I promise...
- Stop it.
- 아프지 않단다
- 하지 마!
- I promise it won't hurt.
- Stop it!
집으로 데려다 줘요
We should take her home.
진정제를 놨어요
I gave her a tranquilizer.
She'll sleep until tomorrow morning.
내일 아침까지 잘거예요
깨기전에 다시 올게요
I'll be here before she wakes up.
아깐 정말 인상적이었어요
You were very impressive back there.
고마워요
Thanks.
But you should've got
that ferry this morning.
내일 아침배로 떠나요
당신도 아다시피, 여기 사람들은
무척 예민해져 있어요
You know, people
are getting nervous around here.
당신이 동요를 일으키고 있어요
You're unsettling them.
I'm unsettling them?
내가 그들을요?
You've had time to gather
your material, you know?
당신은 지금 자료들을
수집하고 있어요, 그렇죠?
You can write
your report now, can't you?
보고서를 지금이라도
작성 할 수 있구요
그런데, 그게 그들하고
무슨 상관이죠?
Well, maybe there's more
at stake than just a report.
이봐요, 내게
조그만 보트가 있소
Look, I've a small boat.
I could easily take you to the mainland.
내가 육지로 태워 주겠소
I can't leave without Dorothy.
도로시만 남겨 놓고
갈순 없어요
Well, the next ferry isn't for three days.
사흘이나 지나야
배가 올거요
Well, then, I'll just have to wait for it.
그러면, 기다리죠 뭐
또 봐요
See you later.
제이크
Jakey.
멋지네
Hey, gorgeous.
Want to party?
놀러 갈까?
Dorothy, you shouldn't be out here...
도로시,
넌 여기서 나가면...
조용히 해
Shut up.
가기나 해
You drive.
Come on.
이리 와
이리 와봐
Come on.
이리 와
Come on. Come on.
가만있어
You really think
I was gonna let a pinhead like you
내가 너한테 줄것 같아?
깡통 대가리야
나랑 하구싶어?
jerk off inside me?
You're a funny boy, Jakey, aren't you?
골 때리는 놈이네
Can't resist.
꿈도 꾸지마1
난 막가는 년이지만
너 한텐 안줘!
I'm desperate,
but I'm not that desperate.
You twisted slut. I'll fucking kill you!
변태 걸레년!
확 죽여 버릴까부다!
You slag!
개 걸레야!
You fucking dirt box!
더러운 년!
여보세요?
Hello?
Dr. Norton?
노튼 박사님?
그런데요, 누구시죠?
Yes, it's me. Who's speaking?
Dorothy tried to kill herself.
도로시가
자살을 시도 했어요
Who is this?
당신 누구야?
당신을 찾아요,
어서 와 줘요
Dorothy needs you. Come quickly.
Dorothy!
도로시!
Why, you must be freezing.
왠일이야,
몸이 얼음장이야
I'm not Dorothy. I'm Kurt.
도로시 아냐, 커트야
What happened, Kurt?
어떻게 된거야, 커트?
When you put Dorothy to bed,
당신이 도로시를
침대 눕히고 나서,
Mary took over
and escaped out the window.
메리가 나타나서
창문으로 탈출했어
What did she do?
메리가 뭘 했는데?
The usual tricks.
뻔한 수법이야
She got arsed with some bloke,
여러명 바보 만들어 놓고
and then vanished
when things got out of hand.
저는 쏙 빠지지
나 몰라라 하구 말이야
Dorothy was so close
to throwing herself off that cliff.
도로시는 절벽에서
떨어지기 일보 직전 이었어
If I hadn't been there to save her...
내가 구했으니 망정이지...
Good man, Kurt.
착하네, 커트
Dorothy will be very proud of you.
도로시가 자랑스럽게
생각 할꺼야
Oh, sweetheart, I'm here.
It's all right now.
오, 귀염둥이야, 나 왔단다
이젠 괜찮아
I'm taking you home.
집으로 가자꾸나
What sort of drug did you give her?
도대체 아이한테
무슨약을 준거죠?
I'm not dead?
나 죽은거 아녜요?
I'm not dead!
나 안죽었네!
No, no, you're not dead.
아니야, 넌 죽지 않았어
But I saw the cliff.
절벽이 보여요
I remember the cliff.
절벽이 기억 나요
I fell off the cliff. I saw the waves.
절벽에서 뛰어 내렸는데
파도가 쳤다구요
Shh. You're safe now. It's okay.
진정해, 이젠 안전해, 괜찮아
No, but I'm a freak.
하지만 전 미쳤잖아요
Nobody can help a freak!
아무도 도움이 안돼요!
You're not a freak, Dorothy, okay?
넌 미친게 아냐, 도로시, 알겠어?
I've done horrible things
I don't even remember.
끔찍한 짓을 저지르고
아무것도 기억을 못한다구요
I'm so ashamed.
너무 수치스러워요
정말 창피스러워요
Listen, Dorothy. Listen carefully to me.
도로시 내 말 잘 들어봐
The things that are happening inside of you
are not your fault.
네 안에서 일어 나는 일들은
네 잘못이 아니야
These blackouts that you have,
네가 겪는 기억상실증은
they're caused
by different characters
각각 다른 성격들이
나타나는건데
that you've created in your mind.
그건 네가 네 마음속에서
만들어내기 때문이야
And when you're scared,
just like now,
지금 처럼
네가 두렵거나 하면,
your... your mind sends out
a character to protect you.
너를 보호 하려고, 네 마음이
성격을 만들어내는거야
But I don't remember anything.
하지만 전 아무것도
기억이 안 난단 말예요
No, but it's because...
아냐, 그건 말이지...
it's because you...
그건 말이야...
- Dorothy.
- No.
- 도로시
- 싫어요
It's because...
그건...
you disappear when that happens.
일이 생길때 넌 없잖아
Dorothy...
도로시...
they're inside of you.
그들은 너 안에 있단다
No. No.
아냐, 아냐
Dorothy, they're trying to keep you
도로시, 그들은
너를 지키려고 해
- from killing yourself.
- It isn't true.
- 자살을 막으려는거야
- 거짓말이야
Dorothy, it was one of these characters
도로시,
이들중 하나가
that hurt this baby, Dorothy, not you.
아기를 해친거야,
도로시 네가 아니야
You mustn't be afraid of them.
그들을 두려워 하면 안돼
그들하고 잘 지내려고
노력해야 돼
Listen, you must try
to relate to them.
손 치우지 못해?
Get your hand off me.
Didn't I already tell you to piss off?
꺼져 버리라고
예전에 말했을텐데?
Duncan, is that you?
던칸, 너야?
Did you hurt the baby?
네가 아기를 해쳤니?
Do you think I hurt the baby?
내가 아기를 다치게 한것 같아?
- Why did you do it?
- How can I do anything?
- 왜 그랬어?
- 내가 뭘 할수 있겠어?
I'm just a character.
그저 성격일뿐인데...
Why did you do it?
왜 그랬어?
Payback.
복수지
Just a little bit of payback.
그저 조금
복수 했을 뿐이라구
What could a baby
have done against you?
아기가 너 한테
무슨짓을 할수 있는데?
You think you're
so fucking smart, don't you?
네가 엄청 똑똑한줄 아나본데..
You don't know anything.
넌 아무것도 몰라
Why don't you take a look
at Dorothy's latest drawing?
왜 도로시가 마지막으로
그린 그림을 안 보는거지?
She did it just for you!
널 위해 그린거야!
귀여운 꼬마 데이빗이야!
Isn't that sweet little David,
floating and dead
죽어서 둥둥 떠다니는군
like a rotten old fish?
썩은 물고기 같지 않아?
엄마, 엄마,
물이 너무 차가워요
Mommy, Mommy, the water is so cold.
- 그만해
- 죽기 싫어요
- Stop it.
- I don't want to die.
Stop it. Stop it!
그만, 그만해!
Don't shout at me, Mommy.
I'm drowning. Help me.
소리 지르지마요, 엄마
저 빠져 죽어요, 살려줘요
Help me. Why did you leave me?
살려줘요,
날 버리고 어디가요?
Don't let me drown.
빠져죽게 내 버려두지 마요
Mommy, help me.
엄마, 살려줘요
Why did you leave me?
날 버리고 어디가요?
Don't let me drown.
빠져죽게 내 버려두지 마요
Please, the water is so cold.
제발요,
물이 너무 차가워요
The water is so cold.
I don't want to die.
죽기 싫어요
Please forgive me.
날 용서해다오
It was my fault.
내 잘못이었단다
I thought it was safe.
안전할거라 생각했었어
Please forgive me.
날 용서해다오
Who is the boy in this photograph?
사진속의 소년은 누구예요?
That's my grandson.
내 손자녀석이라우
날 호수에 쳐박히게 만든
장본인이예요
He's the boy that drove me into the lake,
him and two other kids.
그하고 다른 두명의 친구들...
오, 아녜요
그럴리가 없어요
Oh, no. It couldn't be him.
He's dead this ten years.
그 녀석은
10년전에 죽었다우
기타를 잘 쳤지요
He was good on the guitar.
이름이 뭐 였는데요?
What was his name?
Duncan.
던칸
어떻게 죽었나요?
How did he die?
어이없는 일이었다우
Such a stupid thing.
걔들이 차로 호수에
뛰어 들었어요
They crashed their car into the lake.
They?
그들요?
Duncan and his two young friends,
던칸하고 두 젊은 친구들이었어요
Mary and Kurt.
메리와 커트
아녜요, 말도 안돼요
No, that's impossible.
I saw them in the car in front of me.
그들이 내차로 다가오는걸
분명히 봤단 말이예요
I've seen them in the square.
광장에서도 봤구요
내 말을 못 믿겠으면
신문기사를 보구려
If you don't believe me,
check the records.
시골 청년들 음주사고
가정파괴의 참사
충돌사고로 10대들 사망
You must have told her
about your son.
당신 아들에 대해서
이야기를 해 주었나 보죠
You're the only one
I've mentioned it to.
당신말고 아무한테도
이야기 한적 없어요
And I didn't even
tell you how he died.
당신한테도
어떻게 죽었는지 말 안했구요
You've obviously been going
through too much strain.
당신은 그동안 무리를 해왔어요
Look, you're exhausted,
and your imagination's
당신은 많이 지쳐있고
당신의 그 상상력들은
beginning to play tricks on you.
환각증상을 보이는 겁니다
Tricks?
환각이라구요?
You don't have the slightest idea.
어떻게 그렇게
생각 없이 말할 수 있죠?
These characters
inside of her head are dead.
그들은 그녀 머리속에 있어요
죽은채로요
They're dead!
그들은 죽었다구요!
And these kids that drove me
into the lake, they're dead, too.
그들이 나를 물에 빠뜨렸을때도
그들은 죽은 상태였다구요
하나로 있다가
불쌍한 도로시를 변화 시키죠
And they're the ones
that are turning poor Dorothy
into a fucking ventriloquist!
마치 복화술을
하는것 처럼요!
One time she's Mimi,
then she's Kurt,
한번은 미미로,
어떤때는 커트로
then she's Duncan, then she's Mary.
던칸이 됐다가,
메리도 됐다가
I've heard them
all speak through her,
모두 그녀를 통해서
말하는 거라구요
and there's not a fucking thing
she can do about it.
그냥 그런게 아니라
그녀가 그렇게 할 수 있다구요
How can you believe that?
어떻게 그런걸 믿죠?
You're the psychiatrist, for fuck's sake.
당신은 정신의학자
아니었던가요?
콜린, 뭔가 사악한 일들이
벌어지고 있어요
Colin, some evil shit is going on.
I swear, she feels people's pain.
맹세컨대, 그녀는
사람들의 고통을 느끼는거예요
I mean, I even heard
my own dead son speak.
죽은 아들 목소리를
직접 들었단 말예요
Jane. Jane, Jane, Jane.
Shh.
Hush.
진정해요
Jane, you have
to get away from here.
여기서 떠나야 해요
내일 제가 섬으로
데려다 줄...
I'm gonna take you
to the mainland tomorrow...
- 싫어요
- 아뇨, 들어봐요
- No.
- No, listen.
I don't like the way people are acting.
사람들이 당신을
그렇게 대하는게 싫어요
여기선 당신이 안전하지 않아요
I don't think you're safe here.
그들이 도로시의
진짜 문제점을 알기나 하나요?
What is their real problem
with Dorothy?
What are they so fucking scared of?
그들은 뭘 두려워 하는거요?
It's old stuff, okay? Local stuff.
전통이예요, 알겠어요?
그냥 지역 전통이라구요
It's like you've lifted a stone
and exposed something.
당신 혼자 힘으로
그걸 깨뜨릴순 없어요
I can't believe it's Dorothy.
도로시가 그렇다는게
믿어지질 않아요
받아요
Here.
잠을 청하는데
도움이 될거예요
These'll help you
get through the night.
여기서 주무세요
You can sleep here.
I'll wake you
first thing in the morning.
아침 일찍 깨워 드릴께요
Trust me.
날 믿어봐요
We'll make decisions in the morning.
결정은 아침에 내립시다
Okay.
알았어요
안돼!
No!
뱃져!
Badger!
콜린, 염병할 촌놈아!
Colin, you fucking loser!
Get them, Colin!
Oh.
도로시만 놔두고 갈수가 없어요
- 제인 -
도로시를 병원에
데려갈 생각이예요
I'm going to take Dorothy
back with me to the hospital.
With the right treatment there,
제대로된 치료를
받게 할거예요
도움이 될겁니다
I'm confident we can help her.
도로시를 위해서 좋은일이예요,
맥 마흔부인
It's for her own good, Mrs. McMahon.
제가 도로시의 다중인격을
규명할수 있다면
If I can prove this is a case
of multiple personality,
그녀의 면책에
큰 도움이 될겁니다
there's a good chance she'll be acquitted.
도로시의 능력을
독차지 하려는거죠?
You want to keep her gift
all to yourself, don't you?
I couldn't bear to lose
my Mary all over again.
메리를 다시 볼수 없다는걸
견딜 자신이 없어요
무슨 소리예요
도로시 이야기를 하는거예요
We're talking about
Dorothy, Mrs. McMahon.
Well, my little Mary died 10 years ago.
내 딸 메리는
10년전에 죽었답니다
그녀를 다시는
볼수 없을줄 알았어요
I thought I'd never see her again.
But the good Lord brought Dorothy
into my home as a gift.
하지만 전능하신 하나님께서
도로시를 통해 선물로 보내셨어요
She's worked miracles for me.
도로시는
내게 기적을 행한거예요
She's made your son
speak, hasn't she?
도로시가 당신의
아들 목소리를 들려줬죠?
David.
데이빗
That's his name, isn't it?
그애 이름이죠, 맞죠?
맞죠?
Isn't it?
도로시에 대한일만 생각합시다
We have to think about Dorothy.
We have to help her.
그녀를 도와야 돼요
잘 돌볼게요
I'll take good care of her.
어서 여길 떠나셔야 해요
You've gotta get away from here.
당신한테 죽음의 그림자가
드리워져 있어요
I've seen death
cast its wings on you.
뭐였니, 도로시?
What is it, Dorothy?
Is it the water?
물이야?
- And the blood?
- I'm scared.
- 그리고 피도 나고?
- 무서워요
기억하고 싶지 않아요
I don't want to remember.
I'm scared.
무서워요
괜찮단다
It's okay.
You've gone through it once.
다시 거슬러 올라가봐
And you can live it
again through memory.
기억을 더듬을 수 있을거야
I want to take you
back in time, Dorothy.
과거로 가는거야, 도로시
I'll count from 10 to 1.
열을 셀거야
Where are you?
지금 어디에 있어?
사고가 있었어요
There was an accident.
My mother is washing
the dead people.
엄마가 죽은 사람들을 닦고 있어요
- How old are you?
- I'm 5.
- 넌 몇살인데?
- 다섯살요
- 아는 사람들이니?
- 네
- Do you know them?
- Yes.
봐라, 도로시
너무 아름답지 않니?
Look, Dorothy. Aren't they beautiful now?
They've a long journey ahead of them,
긴 여행을 떠나는거지
죽음의 왕국을 향한 여행...
to the realm of the dead.
Shall we say good-bye to them?
우리 작별인사 하지 않으련?
No...
싫어...
Don't be scared, Dorothy.
겁내지 마라, 도로시
Look. It's your cousin Mary.
봐, 네 사촌언니 메리쟎니?
Give her a kiss good-bye.
직별의 키스를 해주렴
- 싫어
- 키스하렴
- No.
- Give her a kiss.
No!
싫어!
도로시, 그녀에게
작별키스 해주렴
Dorothy, give her a kiss good-bye.
여기도
Come on.
Shh. It's over now.
자, 다 끝났어
It's over now. Dorothy. Shh.
자, 다 끝났어, 도로시
- 자
Shh.
넌 시체에 키스한적이 없어
You didn't kiss the dead bodies.
네가 마음속에서 미미라는
작은소녀를 만든거야
Your mind created Mimi
as a tiny little girl
who doesn't have
the slightest idea about death.
누가 죽음앞에서
그런 하찮은 생각을 하겠어
She kissed the dead for you.
넌 너의 죽음과 키스를 한거야
네
Yeah.
It's all over now.
다 끝났단다
자, 이제 그만 자렴
Shh. Go to sleep. Go to sleep.
내일 아침에 떠날거야
We'll leave tomorrow morning.
Shh.
안녕, 콜린
Evening, Colin.
날 잊진 않았겠지?
Remember me?
- 안돼...
- 내 기억에 넌 겁이 었었는데
- No...
- You weren't so scared
when you were with your three mates.
네 잘난 세친구들 하고
있을때는 말야
No.
안돼
이건 환상이야
You're not real.
Don't pretend you've forgotten,
you fucking piece of shit!
잊어 버린척 하지마,
이 양아치 새끼야!
넌 죽었어
You're dead.
메리도 죽고,
너희 모두 죽었어
Mary's dead. You're all dead.
돌아왔지
We're back.
We've been waiting for you.
이날을 기다리고 있었어
복수의 시간을 말이야...
Time for payback...
Sheriff.
보안관 나으리
You tell us who's next!
다음이 누구 차례인지 말해봐!
It's up to you.
복도에 사람이 죽어 있어요
There's a man lying dead in the hall.
You tell us who's next.
다음이 누구 차례인지 말해봐!
어떻게 해야 하는지
말 안해줄거야!
Don't you tell us what to do!
조용히, 모두 조용히!
Quiet, every one of you!
Dorothy, tell me what happened.
도로시, 무슨일인지
이야기 해다오
I don't know. I don't know.
전 몰라요, 정말 몰라요
눈 보니깐, 죽어 있었어요
When I woke up, he was dead.
She's got to be stopped.
말도 안돼는 소리야
우리가 오기전에
먼저 와 있었어요!
Before she comes after all of us!
자살한게 안 보여요?
Can't you see he killed himself?
Dorothy's not the problem.
도로시는 아무 잘못 없어요
당신들, 당신들 모두예요!
It's you! It's all of you!
그녀는 당신들 친교회의
진실을 알고 있어요
She knows the truth
about your community.
도로시는 제 에미 처럼 제정신이 아냐
Dorothy is a lunatic,
just like her mother,
당신도 알잖아
and you know that.
도로시는 우리 친교회 구성원이네
Dorothy's a member of our community.
그녀 문제도 친교회에서 처리 해야돼
It's our responsibility to deal with her.
던칸 맥클레인이요
My name is Duncan McLellan.
Oh, Duncan.
오, 던컨
My dear Duncan...
우리 애기 던칸...
나 역시 당신들 친교회 구성원이었지
I was a member
of your community, too.
We're listening, Duncan.
듣고 있네, 던칸
보여줄게 있어
I'll show you.
Tell us, Duncan.
말해봐, 던칸
Why did you hurt
the Kearsleys' baby?
키슬리씨네 아기를 왜 해쳤지?
그 애비가 빚진게 있지
His father had to pay.
메리에게 한짓 때문에 모두 빚을 졌지!
They all had to pay
for what they did to Mary!
와우! 잘한다, 메리!
Yeah! Come on, Mary!
Whoo!
꺼져!
Get the fuck away!
- Whoo-hoo!
- Whoo!
Whoo!
Why don't you give us a dance?
왜 우리랑은 춤을 안추는거지?
Just piss off, would you?
안 꺼질래?
웃기고 있네!
Slapper!
던칸?
Duncan?
커트!
Kurt!
너희들 왜 숨고 지랄이야?
Why the fuck are
youse hiding from me?
너희들 끼리 어디서
퍼 마시고있는거지?
Keeping all the booze
to yourselves, is it?
Lads!
얘들아!
썅!
Fuck it.
- Hey! Come back and dance.
- Fuck off!
- 이봐! 다시 춰봐!
- 엿 먹어!
말 조심 하는게 좋을껄, 이 걸레야
Better watch your language, you slut.
Yeah, be polite to me friend.
그래, 얌전히 굴어야지
- 야! 난 갈거야,
너희들 뭐하는 거야?
Hey! Let go of me, will you?
저리가!
Get the fuck off me!
저리가란 말야!
Duncan! Duncan!
던칸! 던칸!
그녀를 놔줘!
Leave her alone!
Jesus!
맙소사!
보내줘! 안 그러면 놈은 죽어!
Let her go! Or I swear I'll kill him!
Let her go, lads! Let her go!
보내줘,얘들아! 보내줘!
Back off! Back off!
물러서! 물러서란 말야!
I'll cut his throat.
모가지를 잘라 버리겠어
털가면 나부랭이들!
Fucking shag this!
I'll fucking kill him for that!
죽여 버리겠어!
이젠 어쩔수 없어
This is getting out of hand, lad.
He tried to kill you.
Are you with us or not?
우릴 죽이려 들거야
같이 할꺼야, 말꺼야?
괜찮아! 다 끝난 일이야!
It's okay! It's over now!
바짝 쫒아 왔잖아!
They're riding our backside!
빨리 가!
Hurry up!
Faster! Speed it up, man!
더 빨리! 더 밟을 수 없어!
Try the fucking gas!
- 최대한 해봐!
- 더 빨리!
Faster!
I can't go faster!
- 최대한 가는거야!
Hurry! Just step on it!
빨리! 더 밟아 봐!
Step on it!
밟으라구!
오, 하나님
Oh, God.
빨리 가!
우릴 죽일거라구!
Hurry up!
They're gonna kill us!
당신...
You...
네 놈이 우리 딸을 죽였어
You killed my daughter.
네 놈이 죽였다구!
You killed my daughter!
커트, 내 아들
Kurt. My Kurt.
우린 철딱서니가 없었어요!
We were just young and stupid!
We didn't mean...
그럴려고 그런건...
용서해줘, 던칸, 제발!
Forgive us, Duncan, please!
던칸!
Duncan!
- 나쁜 자식
- 날 놔줘
- You bastard.
- Get away from me.
떨어져!
Stay away!
메리 맥 마흔은
그래도 싸!
Mary McMahon was up for it!
Oh...
그래...
you bunch of hypocrites.
모두 위선을 떨고 있구만
우리가 그짓 할때
모두 눈도 깜짝 안했잖아!
You didn't bat an eye
when we took her away, did you?
그렇지?
Hmm?
너희들 모두 그여자한테
그래도 된다고 생각했잖아
You all thought she deserved it.
Didn't you!
그랬잖아!
우린 모두가 함께야
We're all in this together.
한배를 탄거라구
Together.
We can keep this on the island.
이 섬을 지켜야 해요
- 그녀가 유일한 증거예요
- 도로시!
- She's the only evidence.
- Dorothy!
제발! 제발, 해치지 말아요!
Please! Please, don't touch her!
두고 가지 마세요! 제발요!
You leave her alone! Please!
- Hush, woman!
- Don't touch her!
- 아줌마, 조용히 해요!
- 해치지 말아요!
Think about it now.
잘 생각 해보세요
Huh? Do you really want
all the publicity?
네? 정말 다 까발려지길
원하세요?
그래요?
Hmm?
Policemen?
경찰?
Journalists?
기자들?
Huh?
그런거야?
All poking their noses
all around this island?
온갖 떨거지들이
섬을 온통 쑤시고 다닐텐데요?
Our island?
우리들의 섬을?
목사님의 작은 친교회의
종말이 되겠지요
It'll be the end
of your happy little community.
지금 잘 생각 하셔야 합니다
Huh? Think about that now.
그녀는 유일한 증거이고
She's the only evidence.
You leave her alone!
그녀를 내 버려 둬!
This is a time of tribulation.
고난의 시기입니다
Fear and anger
공포와 분노가
유대감으로 살아온
우리들을 위협하고 있습니다
threaten to drive apart
those who have lived in fellowship
for many, many years.
수년동안 말입니다
We cannot let this pass.
그냥 넘어가선 안됩니다
For the sake
of the island, we must act.
섬의 안위를 위해
우린 행동해야 합니다
We must right this wrong.
옳던 그르던 간에...
We will not hand you to the police.
자네들을 경찰에 인계하지 않겠네
But you cannot stay here.
하지만 이곳을 떠나게
You will be exiled
from this place forever,
자네들은 이곳에서
영구히 추방 되는걸세
you and your families.
자네들과 자네들 식구
모두 떠나게
Your homes will be leveled.
자네들 집은
허물어 버릴것이고
All memory of you will be erased.
모든 기억은 지워 버릴걸세
If any man should disagree with this,
여기에 동의 하지 않는자가 있다면,
let him speak now.
지금 이야기 하시오
We have all sinned.
우리 모두가 죄인이고
And we shall all suffer.
우리 모두가 고통을
분담 해야 합니다
So let us now devote ourself
더욱 더 정진하여
믿음으로 하나님을 따릅시다
to the worship of the Lord our God,
in the hope of redeeming
ourselves in His eyes.
우리의 허물을
덮어 주시길 기원 합시다
As for the psychiatrist,
정신과 의사에 관한 부분은,
it was her own stubbornness
그녀가 너무나 완강하게
and refusal to listen to reason
변명 같은건
들으려 하지 않는 바람에
which brought her to tragedy.
그런 비극이 일어났습니다
Suffice to say
굳이 말하자면...
she left us without word
of her destination.
행선지를 밝히지 않고
어디론가 떠난 겁니다
No.
안돼
아냐, 말도 안돼
No. It's not possible.
나 죽은거야?
I'm dead?
I'm so sorry, Jane.
미안해, 제인
It's all my fault.
전부 내 잘못이야
I should've stopped you
from going on that damned island.
그 망할 섬에 가는걸
말렸어야 했는데...
I feel so guilty.
자책하고 있어
Don't say that.
그런말 하지마
I'm happy you sent me.
날 보내줘서 행복했어
난 데이빗을 못 구했잖아,
당신도 알지?
I couldn't save David, you see.
하지만 도로시는 구했잖아
But at least I saved Dorothy.
내가 그녀를 구한거, 맞지?
I saved her, didn't I?
그래, 당신이 구했어
You saved her.
당신이 그녈 데려왔어
You brought her back to me.
She'll be acquitted,
무혐의 처분 될거야,
and she'll stay here
until she's cured.
그리고 완치될때까지
여기에 머무를꺼야
그래요
Yeah.
이젠 당신 하기에
달렸어, 제인
And now it's up to you, Jane.
You have to leave Dorothy's body.
도로시의 육체를 떠나야해
당신이 머물러 있으면
그녀는 자유롭지 못해
She won't be free until you're gone.
잘 보살펴 줄꺼죠?
Will you take good care of her?
I promise.
약속할께
Keep it.
잘 간직해요
데이빗이 당신을
많이 사랑했어요
David loved you so much.
I'll keep it forever.
영원히 간직할께
안녕, 내 사랑
Good-bye, my love.
도로시?
Dorothy?
너니?
Is that you?
Has Jane been crying?
제인이 울었군요?
She was here.
여기에 있었어
She's gone now.
금방 떠났어
아들하고 같이 있을거예요,
데이빗이랑...
She's with her son... David.
그들 모두가 떠난것 맞죠?
Do you think they're all gone?
Duncan and Kurt
던칸과 커트
and Mary?
메리도?
And Mimi, too?
미미도 같이죠?
도로시 이제부터는, 너 자신을
위해 사는법을 배워야해
You have to learn to live
on your own now, Dorothy.
넌 자유란다
You're free.
No charm
No spell
Never
Harm
Come our
Lovely
Lady
Nigh
Philomel
With melody
Sing in our sweet
lulla-lulla-lulla
Sing in our sweet lullaby
Come our lovely
Lady nigh
So, good night,
with lulla-lulla-lulla
So good night
with lullaby
Weaving
Spiders
Come not here
Beetles black
Approach not near
Worm nor snail
Do not offend
Sing in our sweet
lulla-lulla-lulla
Sing in our sweet lullaby
Come our lovely
Lady nigh
So good night with
lulla-lulla-lulla
So good night
with lullaby
Now all
Is well
Lovely
Night